Guide to the Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers TAM.544
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers
1970s-1990s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Moser, Richard R., 1952-
TAM.544
4.5 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Richard Moser was an associate professor of American history at Middle Tennessee State University until 1998, and the author of The New Winter Soldiers: GI and Veteran Dissent during the Vietnam Era (1996). About one half of the collection consists of oral histories on audiocassettes the majority pertaining to the GI anti-Vietnam War movement, with some pertaining to rank and file labor movement activity during the 1970s at the Lordstown, Ohio General Motors plant there, whose workers were represented by United Automobile Workers Local 112. There are also research notes, some correspondence, printed ephemera, and papers written by Moser's students.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Richard Moser in 2010. The accession number associated with this gift is 2010.054.
Historical/Biographical Note
Richard Moser earned his PhD from Rutgers University in 1992. Until 1998, he was an associate professor of American history at Middle Tennessee State University. He is the author of The New Winter Soldiers: GI and Veteran Dissent during the Vietnam Era (1996) and, with Van Gosse, is coeditor of The World the Sixties Made: Politics and Culture in Recent America (2003). He has also served as the National Organizer, American Association of University Professors.
Scope and Contents
About one half of the collection consists of oral histories on audiocassettes (there are also summaries and some transcripts), most pertaining to the GI anti-Vietnam War movement, with some pertaining to rank and file labor movement activity during the 1970s at the Lordstown, Ohio General Motors plant, whose workers were represented by the United Automobile Workers Local 112. Some interviews were conducted contemporaneously, others subsequently. There are also research notes, some correspondence, printed ephemera, and papers written by Moser's students.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Separated Materials
One box of GI anti-Vietnam War serials were separated to the Library's print collection, as was one box of books and pamphlets.
Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Protest movements |z United States.; Soldiers |z United States |x Political activity.; Lordstown (Ohio); Automobile industry workers |z Ohio |z Lordstown.; Oral histories (document genres); Audiocassettes.; Videocassettes.; Interviews.; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 1112 (Lordstown, Ohio); Moser, Richard R., 1952-
- Lordstown Oral Histories, cuid15025; 583959 (Box 1)
- Vietnam GI movement Oral Histories, 583960 (Box 2)
  - Cline #1, Mar 1, 1988; cuid15026; 591612 (Box 2, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Dave Kline #4, Mar 1, 1988; cuid15027; 591613 (Box 2, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Dave Cline #3, Feb 15, 1988; cuid15028; 591614 (Box 2, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Susan Schnall Part 1, Oct 25, 1990; cuid15029; 591615 (Box 2, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Susan Schnall Part 2, Oct 25, 1990; cuid15030; 591616 (Box 2, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Jan Berry, undated; cuid15038; 2 audiocassette Parts 1-4 of interview (Box 2, Cassette cuid15038A, cuid15038B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid15038A, cuid15038B)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min. [A] and 46 min. [B]
- Vietnam GI movement Oral Histories, 583961 (Box 3)
  - Jim Pechin, Notre Dame, 1993-12-04; cuid15039; 1 audiocassette (Box 3, Cassette cuid15039, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid15039)
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 50 min.
- Vietnam War Videocasettes: Documentaries, cuid15031; 583962 (Box 4)
- The Invisible Force, cuid15032; 546994 (Box 4)
- Only the Beginning, cuid15033; 546995 (Box 4)
- "Veterans," film transfer Jun 27, 1991, cuid15034; 546996 (Box 4)
- Disobeying Orders: GI Resistance to the Vietnam War, Produce by Pam Sporn, cuid15035; 546997 (Box 4)
- Vietnam GI Movement Research Files (including interview summaries and transcripts), cuid15036; 583963 (Box 5)
- Lordstown Research Files (including interview summaries and transcripts), cuid15037; 583964 (Box 6)